George Binakis

111 North High Street Columbus, OH 43215

Tel # 267.398.4779

Gbinakis3@gmail.com

Profile: A Self-motivated construction professional with a unique combination of management and technical skills, bringing to the table the ability to combine leadership, project management, and development. Extensive experience in multiple sectors including Multifamily, Education, Industrial, Commercial, Healthcare, and Retail. Solid planning and organization skills, for coordinating each project from inception through completion. Excels in learning and adapting to different challenges, being involved within many ongoing projects of various scales.

SUMMARY OF SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS

Technical:

- Project Scheduling and Management
- Project Conformance and Quality Control
- Budget and Materials Management
- Interpretation of Architectural and Engineering Blueprints
- Implementation of Construction Documents
- Value Engineering and Cost Estimating
- Vendor, Sub-Contractor, and Client Relations
- Submittal & RFI Management
- Estimating and Take-offs.

Business/Financial:

- Change Order Management
- Budget and ACR Management
- Creating GMP and Lump Sum Bids
- Staff Management and Recruitment
- Prioritize and execute tasks in High Pressure Environments
- Design and Work effectively in Team Oriented, Collaborative Environments
- Team Development and Coordination
- Cash Flow Management
- Business Development
- Organizational Skills

EXPERIENCE

Elford, Inc Project Manager February, 2022 - Present

Project Manager responsible for overseeing (2) multi-family developments in the short north area, starting from Pre-construction phases, GMP establishment, and through oversight of all operations. Both developments are concrete podiums with parking levels below grade, and residential apartment levels above (wood frame).

- Assisted estimating and precon manager with constructability reviews
- Facilitated all bid reviews with superintendent and APM to establish final GMP

- Generated Baseline schedule with monthly baseline comparisons
- Managed all change management from PCI OCO, including SCO; s
- Responsible for all budget management including preparation of monthly project status reports with leadership team
- Oversight and management of RFI and Submittal process with APM's, including high level coordination with design team and subs
- Coordinated with BIM process
- Led OAC's and assisted APM with subcontractor meetings
- Coordinated with superintendent to update schedule
- Coordinated with superintendents and APM through QAQC process
- Developed staffing plans, work schedules, budgets, and timelines
- Negotiated contracts that ensured quality and met standards

Triton Construction Project Manager

March, 2018 - December, 2021

Project engineer and manager responsible for maintaining quality control related to budget, scheduling, and coordination for a new 57 story residential Condominium development for Tishman Speyer.

- Prepare, schedule, coordinate, and monitor assigned construction trades, complying with applicable codes, practices, performance standards, and specifications.
- Responsible for managing all RFI, submittals, and change orders related to the project
- Maintained cost control and monitored weekly budget shifts
- Organized and managed weekly progress meetings with the ownership and the design team to review scheduling, critical issues, RFI,s and ASI's
- Ensuring all procedures and calculations are submitted to the client for review and approval
- Coordinates with all project related personnel (onshore and offshore) on day-today progress of work activities, procurement and operations to ensure timely completion of the project.

Triton Construction Senior Project Engineer May 2016 – December, 2017

Sikanib General Contracting, Inc. Project Manager

Mar. 2006 – April, 2016

- Evaluate project documents and drawings; assess scope of work, schedule required resources and determine project objectives, long lead and potential cost escalation items, and project schedules.
- Develop cost estimates, drawings, and proposals and prepare budgets, contracts, and purchase orders; maintain project documentation and records.
- Communicate with owners, management, and contractors to provide progress reports and answer questions about the status of the project.
- Manage budget for change orders and collaborate with architects and engineers.
- Plan, acquire and satisfy permitting, building requirements, and codes in Manhattan, NY;
 maintain open communications with city inspectors and key personnel.

- Identify, supervise and schedule work and progress of subcontractors and trades; conduct site inspections and monitor and control project safety, quality, budgets, and direct costs.
- Implement quality assurance procedures to make sure that all stages and phases of the project are executed as per specification using good workmanship

Sikanib General Contracting, Inc. Assistant Project Manager / Superintendent

Summer 2002 - Dec. 2005

- Assisted in managing and inspecting all work pertaining to each specific project.
- Responsible for sequencing all construction tradesmen and sub-contractors appropriately
- Ensured all work was done as per provided specifications and drawings.
- Responsible for preparing daily reports, schedules, material ordering, and change orders.
- Assisted in layout and all aspects of framing and carpentry.
- Delivered materials and tools when necessary.
- Organized and managed all correspondence from project trailer main office

Diontech Consulting:

Summer/Fall 2004

Foreman

- Assisted small construction firm in layout and framing.
- Ensured all walls and ceilings were framed as per drawings.
- Scope of work included supervision of metal framing, installing Gypsum Boards, plywood subfloors, wood joists, and painting

EDUCATION

<u>Farmingdale State University</u> – School of Engineering Technology - *Graduated Summer, 2007* Bachelor of Science – Civil Engineering technology

Fiorello H. Laguardia High School

Spring 2003

New York, NY 10023 High-School Diploma

LICENCES, CERTIFICATIONS AND SPECIAL QUALIFICATIONS

- Expert in Procore Project Management Software
- Expert in P6 Scheduling
- Expert in CMiC Management Software
- Expert in Bluebeam Revu
- Proficient in Microsoft Project Scheduling Software
- Proficient in MS Word, Excel, and Power-Point
- Fluent in English, Spanish, and Greek
- OSHA 30 Hour Construction Safety Certified
- Certified in Lead Safe Work Practices -Certification # LSWP-1246